LAM WAI MEI, MAVIS

Contact No.: +852-6139-9725 Email: mavislam129@gmail.com

PERSONAL PROFILE

A highly motivated person and dedicated individual with strong analytical and communication skills A good team player with a can-do attitude and active learning

Possess solid experience in the field of fund operation with in-depth knowledge of Equity, Fixed Income, Money Market Fund and Derivatives

Strong ability in handling multi-task assignments under aggressive deadline

WORK EXPERIENCE

10/2015 – Present Zurich Services (HK) Limited

Assistant Manager, Investment Accountant (Full time)

- Regional role in the Investment Management department
- Led the team projects by understanding the business requirements and performed testing and analysis within the timeframe
- Coordinate the team to resolve project issue and support test case formulation
- Participated in system enhancements and perform UAT
- Performed investment analytic reports to Investment Managers
- Independently managed clients' queries and maintained good client relationship for APAC
- Prepared accounting valuation according to local and international accounting standard (e.g. IFRS, HKGAAP, etc), particularly in APAC and European clients
- Worked closely with the clients to prepare the countries regulatory reports (Australian Prudential Regulation Authority (APRA), Monetary Authority of Singapore (MAS), Swiss Solvency II, etc)
- Reviewed existing workflow and explored solution to improve the current processes to improve efficiency
- Coordinated annual audit, SOX testing and ad hoc compliance reporting

06/2010 – 10/2015 State Street Asia Limited

Assistant Manager, Fund Accountant (Full time)

- Expertise in delivering query management to APAC clients and liaise with Investment Managers, and internal parties to resolve the issues
- Understanding the client requirements and drafted the Business Requirement Documents (BRD), reviewed Business Solution Document (BSD) and performed User-Acceptance Tests (UAT)
- Supported the business transformation projects (e.g. migration project, system enhancement projects, project revamp, etc)
- Experienced in reconcile and resolve the discrepancy of cash / security position and followed up on the resolution of outstanding items
- Reviewed existing workflow and explored solution to streamline the process to improve efficiency and drafted the detailed plan to implement
- Performed oversight function to monitor the service level provided by the processing centers
- Prepared fund valuation, financial Statement, cash flow report and other client reports for the APAC clients

LAM WAI MEI, MAVIS

Contact No.: +852-6139-9725 Email: mavislam129@gmail.com

- Responsible for transactions processing, including securities trades, cash movement, foreign exchange, etc.
- Monitored and reviewed the exception reports to ensure data quality and investigated the exceptional issues
- Reviewed the standard operation procedures and the control procedures periodically to ensure data accuracy and efficiency
- Reviewed the worked performed by the juniors and trained the new hires

08/2009 - 05/2010

Audit Junior (Full time)

Lily Tsang & Co CPA

- Performed book-keeping of accounts
- Prepared financial statement and accounting reports
- Prepared audit working papers and performed audit procedures including transaction test and tracing original evidence into the records
- Reported the findings during audit to seniors

06/2008 - 08/2008

Audit Intern (Internship)

BDO Raffles, Singapore

- Reviewed documents and processed data for audit field works
- Prepared audit working papers for clients specialized in computer software and industrial materials manufacturing
- Performed audit procedures including test of controls and transaction tests

EDUCATION

2007 – 2009 BBA (Hons) Accountancy, City University of Hong Kong

- Graduation with Upper Second Class Honours
- CGPA 3.04/4.0

2005 - 2007

Associate Degree in China Business Management, Community College of

City University

- Graduation with Distinction
- CGPA 3.46/4.0

1997 - 2005

Form 1 - Form 7, Methodist College

OVERSEAS EXCHANGE

09/2006 - 12/2006

Shanghai University, China

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION

Member

Hong Kong Institute of Certified Public Accountants (HKICPA)

PC SKILLS

Microsoft Office: Outlook, Word, Excel & Powerpoint Accounting Software: DacEasy, PeachTree, SAP Software

LANGUAGES

Fluent in Cantonese, English, Putonghua

AVAILABILITY

One Month Notice